那后来呢
So then what happened?
第二天她没来学校
Well she didn't show up to school the next day.
我听说她是在他宿舍过的夜
And I heard that she slept over at his dorm.
不是吧
No way.
说真的  你居然会觉得惊讶
Seriously, are you surprised?
你还不认识卡莉吗
Do you not know Carley?
没看她在学校都穿些什么
Have you not seen what she wears at school?
姑娘们  别八卦了行吗
Girls, let's cool it on the gossip, okay?
背后说人闲话不好
It's not right.
再说卡莉麻烦已经够多了
And Carley's got enough problems.
什么意思
What do you mean?
她妈妈当年足球训练
Well, her mom can't get through soccer practice
必须靠酒才能挺过去
without a thermos of chardonnay,
更别提他爸爸了  那家伙实在
And don't get me started on the dad. That guy is--
-老天啊  -天啊
- Oh, my god! - Oh, my god!
-妈  -这十字路口太危险了
- Mom! - Oh! This is such a dangerous intersection!
我脸上有口红印吗
Did I get lipstick on my face?
没有  美着呢  庆幸吧
No, you're fine. And consider yourself lucky
你刚才至少没被妈妈袭胸
you didn't just get, like, felt up by your mom.
这里应该立个停车标志
They need to get a stop sign.
你怎么老纠结于交通问题
What is your obsession with traffic?
是纠结于安全问题
It's an obsession with safety.
早晚有一天  那些飙车族冲出来
One of these days, joe speeder's gonna come tearing through here,
总有人会被  天啊
and somebody's gonna--aah! Aah!
我没事
I'm okay.
-我的天啊  -我没事  是你们啊
- Oh, my god! I'm okay. - Oh, hey, guys.
-菲尔  -我没事  我得接着走了
- Phil? - Yeah. No, I'm good. Gotta keep moving.
维持高心率运动
Keep the heart rate up.
好吧
Oh. Okay.
我脸怎么样
How's my face?
风姿依旧
Still good.
那就好
Okay. Good.
歌洛莉亚  跟你说了好多遍了
Gloria, how many times do I have to tell you
车身要全部停进来
to pull your car all the way in?
院门又开了一整晚
The gate was open all night.
我们住在五好社区
We live in a nice neighborhood.
还怕什么  害怕钱像潮水般涌进来
What are you afraid of? That some money's gonna fly in
园丁要忙于挥耙清理吗
and then your gardener is gonna have to rake it up?
杰  帮我开张支票
Jay, I'm going to need you to cut me a check.
又怎么了
What now?
戏剧社活动  去看《悲惨世界》
Drama club trip. "Les miserables."
票钱要靠自己推销包装纸来募集
We're selling wrapping paper to raise money for the tickets.
等等  慢慢说  是怎么个事儿
No. No. Wait. Wait. Slow down. What's the story exactly?
冉阿让因为偷了一条面包
Well, Jean Valjean spent 19 years in prison
在监狱里被关了19年
for stealing a loaf of bread.
我是问包装纸
The wrapping paper.
被关19年就为吃条面包
19 years for a loaf of bread?
什么面包这么好吃
How good was this bread?
跟面包无关  故事旨在揭露这个社会
It wasn't about the bread. It was about the society--
别跑题  各位
Focus, people.
曼尼  我们会买下你全部的包装纸
Manny, we will buy all your wrapping paper.
不  这样不行  他得学着自己卖
No. No, we won't. No, he's got to learn to sell.
这是锻炼营销技巧的绝好机会
This is the best business training there is,
更是一次绝佳的人生历练
hell, the best life training.
曼尼  把这话记下来
Manny, write this down--
"优秀推销员一名  驾驭划艇猎白鲸
"A good salesman goes after Moby Dick in a rowboat
塔塔美酱随身行"
and brings the tartar sauce with him."
杰老是让我随听随记
Jay is always telling me to "Write this down."
但有时候  他说的话我理解无能
I don't always catch everything he says.
"什么什么紧握双手"
"Something, something, firm handshake."
"看房莫止第一屋"
"Never take the first room they show you."
也不知道看谁的房
Not sure who "They" Is.
还有这句  就两个字"煎饼"
And this one just says "Pancakes."
小卡  《名利场》封面上什么领养机构的涂鸦
Cam, what's this scribble on the "Vanity fair"
是怎么回事
about an adoption agency?
对了  他们打电话来说
Oh, um, yeah, they called to say
家访时间有变
they wanted to reschedule our home visit.
什么时候  你怎么没告诉我
When? Why didn't you tell me?
这么重要的事
Th-this is kind of important.
上面写的是什么时候
Well, when does it say?
谁知道
Uh, well, who knows?
到詹妮弗·安妮斯顿头发那儿就看不清了
It disappears into jennifer aniston's hair.
你以后要换个方法记事
You gotta get a better system.
烂笔头不如好记性
There is nothing wrong with my system.
随便问我什么日程安排
Ask me anything about any upcoming event.
我马上能告诉你时间地点
I can tell you when and where it is.
收养机构家访是什么时间
When is the adoption agency visit?
好的  这是个"5"还是一撮卷发
Okay. Is that a "5" or a curl?
我希望詹妮弗最后能找到真爱
Oh, I hope Jen's finally found love.
这儿发生什么了
What happened here?
一大早起床时  莉莉和我心系法式风情
Well, Lily and I woke up in a French mood,
所以我们决定自制些法国薄饼
so we decided to whip up some crepes.
你什么时候才有心情打扫这些薄饼呢
When are you gonna be in the mood to wipe up some crepes?
我知道这里有点乱  但是
Oh, I know, it's a little messy, but...
-我会打扫干净的  -好的
- you know what? I'm gonna clean it up. - Okay.
-我会打扫的  -你会吗
- I'll clean it up. - Will you?
-心里有话不妨直说  -你不会打扫的
- Just say what's on your mind. - You never clean up.
气结也没用
Save the gasp.
小卡  每次你在厨房研究新菜式
Cam, whenever you get creative in the kitchen,
总是我来收拾残局
I'm the one who ends up cleaning it up, okay?
自制披萨  芝士火锅  分子烹饪  诸如此类
The homemade pizza, fondue, molecular gastronomy.
到现在  窗帘上的虾沫尚未清理干净
I'm still cleaning shrimp foam out of the curtains.
行了  米奇尔  你放心去上班吧
Okay, you know, Mitchell? Just go to work, okay?
我来送莉莉上学  等我回家的时候
I'm gonna take Lily to school, and then when I get home,
我就清理"饭醉现场"  不留蛛丝马迹
I'm gonna scrub this place like a crime scene,
也的确是犯罪现场  因为你扼杀了我的乐趣
which it is, because you've murdered joy.
伙计  干吗呢
Hey, buddy. What's up?
老爸  接招
Hey, dad. Think fast.
我的天啊
Oh, my god!
-好神奇  -太神奇了
- Oh, my god! - Oh, my god!
如果我们把这个录下来了
If we had that on tape,
它肯定会是Youtube史上最佳视频
it'd be the greatest youtube video ever!
会有一百万点击率  直逼《惊现双彩虹》
We'd get, like, a million hits. This is our double rainbow!
我们得再来一遍
We need to do it again.
我也想  伙计  但是
Oh, I would, buddy, but, uh,
你妈妈有好多灯泡要我换呢
Your mom's all over me to change a bunch of lightbulbs.
拧一个灯泡需要几个妈妈
How many moms does it take to screw on a lightbulb?
不知道
I don't know.
一个都不用  因为她会指使你去干  废柴
None, 'cause they get you to do it, sucker.
我强颜欢笑  但是
I laughed, but...
内心在滴血
It hurt a little.
我们回来啦
We're home!
-我们也回来啦  -太好了  人齐了
- Us, too. - Oh, great. You're all here.
怎么了  妹子
What's up, girl?
知道什么是危险十字路吗
Oh. You know that really dangerous intersection?
是说欲恨纠缠  杀意萌生吗
Where desire meets jealousy, and the result is murder?
是说今早我差点撞死你的那个十字路
Mnh-mnh. The one where I almost killed you this morning.
对不起  是我的错  我太入神了
Oh, yeah. Sorry. That was my bad. I got lost in my Jams.
危险组合啊  竞走+摇滚
Dangerous combo-- speed walking and speedwagon.
我当时完全是无意创造出来的
Oh. I wasn't even trying for that.
好赞
Nice.
我要去申请一个停车标志
Well, I am getting us a stop sign.
我打给市政厅了  真是赶得早不如赶得巧
I called City Hall, and how is this for amazing?
交通委员会今晚例会
The Traffic Committee meets tonight.
我内心十分激动
I've got goosebumps.
可不是嘛  现在只要征集50个签名
I know, right? All I have to do is get 50 signatures,
走个过场  事就成了
show up, make my case.
-好戏开始了  -我真为你骄傲
- It's on. - I am so proud of you.
都为你骄傲
We all are. Mm.
妈妈有事做的日子真美好
We love when mom gets on a project.
因为在平时  只要我们一进家门
Because usually the minute any of us walks in the door,
她就会给我们安排事情做
she gives us something to do.
"做作业  扫房间"
"Do your homework. Clean your room."
"穿裤子"
"Put on pants."
又不是觐见女王  那么讲究干嘛
Like the Queen's coming over. Am I right?
一旦她不在家或者忙得顾不得我们
So when she's not around or gets busy,
我和卢克就会抓紧时间狂欢一把
Luke and I capitalize on the situation.
给你  老兄
There you are, my good man.
小卢子  开始行动吧
Squire, let's do it.
尽情吃吧
Get you some!
这计划真好
Well, I think it's awesome.
太好了  我正需要你们帮忙
I am so glad because I could really use your help
征集签名
getting these signatures.
我来吧
I'll do it,
给你换完灯泡后就动手
soon as I change those lightbulbs you wanted.
很好  你们呢
Great. Kids?
真不巧  今天作业都堆成山了
Crud. You know, I've got a ton of homework.
-我有科学小项目  -海莉呢
- Uh, science project. - Haley?
我得准备大学入学申请论文
I need to get started on my college essay.
其实我觉得  可以写写你
You know what? Maybe I'll write it about you.
你的事迹如此鼓舞人心
You're just so inspirational.
女中豪杰  你太有才了
Girl power! You rock.
谢谢  亲爱的
Thanks, honey.
我是很有才
I do rock.
斯黛拉  下去
Stella, down.
斯黛拉  别跳了  很危险
Stella, no. This is very dangerous.
埃斯特拉  够了
Okay, Estella. That's it.
过来  你要是有个三长两短
Come here, because Jay is gonna be very mad
杰会气疯的
if something happens to you.
玩你的骨头去吧  回见
Go play with the bone. See you later.
终于能专心做肉馅卷饼了
Now I can cook my empanadas.
门没关
The gate.
不要啊
Ay, no!
不要啊  忘了关门了
Ay, no! The gate! The gate!
回来啊  斯黛拉
Estella, come back!
怎么样啊  销售员同志
Hey there, Mr. Salesman.
我们不谈生意行吗
Can we not talk about business?
这么糟糕吗
That bad, huh?
我已经尽全力了
I gave it everything I got--
卖萌卖笑都试了
Working the dimples, going big eyes.
结果呢  遭的全是白眼
It got me two things-- diddly and squat.
你去了多少户人家
How many houses you hit?
不知道
I don't know.
最少也有三家
Must've been at least three.
就三家也叫尽全力了
Three? And that's your idea of the best you got?
这对我来说太难了
It was very hard on me.
爬山我身累  被拒我心累
I'm not used to rejection... or hills.
你不能就试了三家就放弃
Look, you can't quit after three houses.
半途而废可不对
That's-- that's not perseverance.
你卖的是什么东西
What are you selling?
-包装纸  -错
- Wrapping paper. - Wrong.
你的卖点是圣诞节
You're selling Christmas--
你卖的是打开礼物的那种喜悦
the excitement of opening presents,
蛋奶酒的醇香
the taste of eggnog.
我喜欢蛋奶酒
I do love eggnog.
把这话记下来
Look, write this down--
成功和尝试的区别在哪里
"What's the difference between 'try' and 'triumph'?"
就差中间使得那把劲
A little oomph?
就差中间使得那把劲  明白了吗
A little oomph. Get it?
我自己说的我当然明白
Of course I get it. I just said it.
笨狗  找到你老娘就把你炖了
Hey! I'm gonna kill you when I find you, silly dog!
快回来吧  斯黛拉
Why don't you come back? Stella!
我有个想法
I have a theory.
真谢谢你过来帮我  小卡
Ay, Cam, thank you for helping me.
乐意之至  斯黛拉
Oh, it's my pleasure. Stella!
斯黛拉
Stella!
我的神啊
Oh, my god.
怎么了  你看见她了吗
What? Do you see her?
没有  但我发现这个角色简直是为我量身订造
No. But I see myself in the role I was born to play.
斯黛拉
Stella!
喂  米奇尔  你猜怎么着
Hello? Oh, Mitchell, you are not gonna believe this.
我正在外面帮歌洛莉亚找她的狗
I'm out helping Gloria look for her dog.
我就只穿着件内衣然后大喊斯黛拉
I'm wearing an undershirt and I'm screaming "Stella,"
就和《欲望号街车》里的场景一模一样
Just like in "Streetcar."
-你在听吗  -你没清理厨房
- Hello? - You didn't clean the kitchen.
米奇尔  我现在斯坦利·科沃斯基附体
Mitchell, I am an inadvertent Stanley Kowalski.
你怎么都不替我高兴
How can you not be delighted by this?
你答应过的
You promised.
我接到紧急呼救
I was called away for an emergency.
歌洛莉亚的狗丢了  她心碎欲死
Gloria's lost her dog, and she's heartbroken.
笨狗  你死哪去了
Where are you, dumb dog?
最好掉进洞里  坑死你
I hope in a big, black hole.
真不敢相信你又干这种事
I cannot believe That you did this to me yet again. Oh.
我什么都没干
I didn't do anything.
我就在厨房做了个饭
I cooked a meal in our kitchen.
然后你就故意甩手不管
And then you left on purpose, knowing that
知道我怕脏乱  会替你收拾
I would not be able to sit here without cleaning it up.
生活本就一团糟  多大的事啊
Life is messy sometimes. Big deal.
总有雾散云开的时候
It gets cleaned up.
几个脏盘子放一放又有什么
You're the one with a problem if you can't leave
忍不了是你自己的问题
a few dirty dishes for a couple hours.
行  小卡  我不清理
O-okay, fine. C-cam, I'm not cleaning it up.
太好了
Great.
我说到做到
I mean it.
太好了  要不这样
Perfect. You know what?
你干脆弄得更乱一点
Why don't you make it bigger?
没问题  我会的
You know what? I will.
行  给我听好了  你就等着吧
I-I... Okay, you know, get--get ready,
等你回家时  这里就会变得脏乱差
Because you are gonna come home to--to a giant mess.
再脏再乱再差  我也欣然接受
And I will give him a giant hug when I get there.
斯黛拉
Stella!
老爸  接招
Hey, dad. Think fast.
哎呦  伙计
Oh. Wow. Buddy.
我不能陪你玩  我说过了要去换灯泡
I'm sorry. I told you, I gotta change the lightbulbs
然后还得帮你妈去弄那些签名
and then help your mom with those signatures.
没关系
Never mind.
反正这主意也不灵光
I guess it was a stupid idea anyways.
我一贯坚持  只要孩子把我
I've always said that if my son thinks of me
和他的狐朋狗友等同视之  我这当爹的就成功了
as one of his idiot friends, then I've succeeded as a dad.
要是他想在电梯上逆着跑  我会跟他一起疯
If he wants to go the wrong way on the escalator, I'm on board.
要是他想跑到餐馆里
If he wants to go into a restaurant
假扮自己是澳大利亚人
and pretend we're Australian.
"你好"[澳大利亚口音]
"G'day mate!"
"给我和我家崽来点儿烤大虾"[澳大利亚口音]
"Toss a few shrimp on the barbie for me and my Joey."
对味吧  妮可·基德曼[澳洲名演员]
Yeah? Right? Nicole Kidman?
群星乐队[澳洲著名乐队]
Men at Work?
第十二条  准备开拍
Here we go. Take 12.
老弟  我回来了
Hey, buddy! I'm home!
老爸  接招
Hey, dad. Think fast.
我的手都酸疼了
Wow. You know, my arm's starting to hurt a little.
是吗  我还没说头疼呢
Really? Cause my face feels great.
得了老爸  咱别相互过不去
Come on, dad. Let's not turn on each other.
还有很长的路要走
We could be here a while.
是啊  好吧  你说得对  接着试
Yeah. Okay. You're right. Here we go.
第九条
Take 9.
你怎么心不在焉的
You're not even trying.
爸爸  我饿了
Daddy, I'm hungry.
宝贝  你想吃什么
What do you want, honey?
葡萄干
Raisins.
好啊  自己去拿吧
All right well, go get 'em.
爸爸  太高了
It's too high, daddy.
我够不着
I can't reach.
声明一下  我这人没洁癖
For the record, I am not a neat freak.
其实  在我第一次谈恋爱时
I-in fact, in my first long-term relationship,
我才是邋遢的那个  所以被妹子甩了
I was the messy one, which is why she broke up with me.
-不必了  谢谢  -好吧
- No, thanks. - Okay.
别急别急  让你瞧瞧我是怎么搞定的
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Let me show you how it's done.
你好  我是杰·普里契特
Hi. Uh, Jay Pritchett here.
节日的气氛越来越浓
Holidays are just around the corner.
不好意思  我不信包装纸这套
I'm sorry. I don't believe in wrapping paper.
啥叫不信包装纸啊
What do you mean you don't believe in wrapping paper?
又不是大脚怪传说  是实用品啊
It's not bigfoot. It exists.
这不环保  很浪费
It's not eco-friendly. It's wasteful.
不不  我卖的可不是
No, not this stuff.
这是百分之百再生纸
This paper was made from 100% recycled materials.
别忽悠了
I don't think so.
我听不懂你在说什么
I can't understand what you're saying.
她是条又丑又小的斗牛犬
She's an ugly little fresh bulldog
长着小耳朵和苦逼脸
with the tiny ears and the smushy face.
这有啥听不懂的
What is so hard to understand?
我很不喜欢别人在我做雕刻的时候
I really don't like people coming to my door unannounced
不请自来
While I'm working on my carving.
我明白  但是停车标志真的很重要
I understand, but a stop sign is really important.
您在忙着雕什么呢
What exactly are you carving?
你好  夫人  你喜欢圣诞节吗
Hello, ma'am. Do you love Christmas?
其实  我是犹太人
Actually, I'm jewish.
这么说  你肯定很爱捡便宜
Oh, well, then you must appreciate a good value.
苍天啊
Oh, jeez.
如果你看到她了  告诉我们一声
If you see her, let us know.
天哪  不  不
Oh, my god. No, no. No, no.
开什么玩笑  有没搞错
Are you kidding? Seriously?!
瞧  你的脑袋没保持在正确的位置
See? You're not keeping your head in the right position.
能认出视频里是我  但当时的场景我已经记不得了
I know that's me, but I'm not remembering any of this.
这群笨蛋邻居
Oh. Those stupid neighbors!
-怎么了  -我要个签名都不行
- What's wrong? - I can't ask for a simple signature.
但他们把房子建得
But it's fine for them to build a house
就像比弗利富豪就可以
that looks like the Beverly hillbillies just moved in.
你们进展如何
Did you do any better?
有几次差点儿成功了
We came close a few times,
不过  你说的不是篮球这档子事对吧
But you're not talking about the basketball, are you?
菲尔  拜托告诉我你拿到了些签名
Phil, tell me you got some signatures.
还有两个小时我就要去市政厅了
I have to be at city hall in, like, two hours.
老天啊  海莉  你那边怎样
Oh, god. Haley, how about you?
我正忙着写高校入学申请论文呢
I've been busy with my college essay.
真的吗  在哪儿呢
Really? Where is it?
目前只有草稿  尚未成型
It's in a rough, rough draft right now.
我在想也许我该写
I've been thinking that maybe that I should--
你出门这会  艾丽克斯一直在男友网聊
Alex has been skyping with her boyfriend since you left.
才不是呢
That's so not true!
谢谢你
Thank you.
真的  非常感谢各位的帮助
Really, thank all of you so much for your help.
不是吧你
Really?
有时候灯泡像车一样  也需要预热一下
Sometimes those things need to warm up, like the car.
菲尔  别鬼扯了  我今天一直在外奔波
Phil, don't even. I have been out there,
为社区邻里谋福利
trying to do something good for our community,
因为改革不会自己发生
because let me tell you, change doesn't just happen.
改革是要靠女权人士来推动的
It is forged by empowered women like me
比如我  诺玛·蕾  还有《弱点》的那位女士
And Norma Rae and the lady from "The Blind Side."
知道我和她有什么不同吗
Do you know what the difference is between me and her?
那位"弱点妈妈"有家人的支持
Blind side's family had her back.
好吧
Okay.
大伙都过来
Huddle up, everybody.
你妈妈说的对
Your mother's right.
家庭似球队  母如四分卫
She's the quarterback of this family,
我们要像"弱点"一样守护她
And we need to protect her like blind side did.
她刚说"弱点"是那个妈妈
She just said the mom was blind side.
她那是气糊涂了
Well, she's confused.
防守球员准备
Offense line.
抱歉  我的小黑孩儿们
Sorry. African-american kid.
她在那边
There she is.
嘿  斯黛拉
Ay! Stella!
谢天谢地  狗被你找到了  多谢你
Ay, thank god you found my dog. Thank you.
这是我的狗  她叫小粉
This is my dog. Her name's pinky.
不  不对  她叫斯黛拉
No, it's not. Her name is stella.
狗牌上写的清清楚楚  看
It says right here on the tag. Look.
等下  抱歉  亲爱的  你叫什么名字
Uh, uh, uh, excuse me. Hi, sweetie. What's your name?
布兰奇[欲望号街车女主角的名字]
Blanche.
太巧了吧  米奇尔上边去
Shut up. Mitchell would die.
听着  我们不认识你
Listen, we don't know you.
但我们觉得小姑娘很乖很听话
You seem like a very sweet little girl,
我们没得选择  只有
And right now we're forced to--
终于说到这句了我好开心
I can't believe I'm saying this to you--
要依赖陌生人的善心[欲望号街车著名对白]
rely on the kindness of strangers.
两百块卖给你们
I'll sell her to you for $200.
够了  把狗还给我
That's it. Give me my dog.
来真的吗  小姑娘当真以为
Oh, really? The little girl thinks because she can scream,
会尖叫就可以不讲理吗  尖叫我也会
she can get away with everything? I can scream, too.
这是什么鸟声音
What the hell sound is that?
估计猫被郊狼逮住了
Coyotes must've got a cat.
杰  我们能停了吗  我饿了
Jay, can we stop now? I'm getting hungry.
知道吗  问题就在于  你卖不出去也不会挨饿
You know what the problem is? You're not hungry.
我只在3点钟时啃过一根胡萝卜
I had a carrot at 3:00.
如果你下笔再卖不出去
What if you couldn't feed your family
全家都要饿肚子怎么办
Unless you made this next sale?
再卖不出去房子就要被收怎么办
What if you were gonna lose your house?
我知道这么教孩子有点太严  但是
I know I was pushing the kid hard, but here's the thing--
我是老来得子  在他身边的日子没那么多了
I'm an older dad. I'm not gonna be around forever.
要确保他有门吃饭的手艺  我才能睡个安稳觉
And I'll sleep better knowing he's got something to fall back on.
快  我们再走一家
Come on! Let's hit another one.
-我做不到  -什么
- I can't do it. - What?
-我没这本事  -这叫什么话
- I don't have what it takes. - What kind of talk is that?
这是事实  杰
It's the truth, Jay.
我不是推销员的料  更不是商人的料
I'm not a great salesman. I'm not a great businessman.
我跟你不一样
I'm not you.
看到你成绩卓越  却知道自己永远无法企及
Do you know what it's like to see all the amazing things
这种感觉你懂不懂
You've accomplished, knowing I never will?
我怎么才能与你比肩
How am I supposed to live up to you?
谁能做出你的成就
How is anyone?
看来鱼今天都不上钩
Ah, so the fish weren't biting today.
那又怎么样  人生不如意者八九
So what? That's life.
重点在于是否为此努力
You tried hard, and that's what matters.
没错
Yeah.
听着  其实我需要一些包装纸
You know, I-I actually need some wrapping paper.
知道从哪能买到吗
You know where I can find some?
-你不用帮我的  -我真心想帮你
- You don't have to do that. - I want to do it.
拍富人马屁  定一本万利
You'll never go broke playing to a rich guy's ego---
把这话记下来
Write that down.
非常感谢大伙
Thanks so much, you guys.
先许个愿吧
Maybe you should make a wish.
打扰一下
Uh, hi. Oh, I'm sorry.
我是来参加交通委员会会议的
Um, I'm here for the Traffic Committee meeting?
已经休会了
The meeting's been adjourned.
-是吗  -我正开生日会呢
- Yeah. Um... - It's my birthday.
我很抱歉  祝你生日快乐
I'm sorry. Happy birthday.
有人把我带到错误的房间去了
Uh, just--someone sent me to the wrong room,
你们下次开会又得等好几个月
and you guys don't meet again for months,
而这事可是生死攸关  迫在眉睫
and this is pretty much a matter of life and death, so...
好吧  随便你
Uh, yeah, it's fine.
只要  你能尽快说完
Uh, just-- if you could make it quick.
这可是冰激凌蛋糕
We--it's an ice cream cake.
-没问题  -其实  这不是冰激凌的
- Okay. - A-actually, it's not.
-什么  -不是冰激凌
- What? - No.
真的吗  那我们就没什么可急的了
Really? Oh, then we-- we're not in a rush, I guess.
完全不用急  慢慢来  说吧
At all. No rush. Go ahead.
太好了  我叫克莱尔·邓菲
Great. My name is Claire Dunphy,
我家就住在离那个危险十字路
and my family and I live near
-不远的地方  -为啥不买冰激凌的
- that intersection of -- - Why not? Why not?
冰箱坏了  没法保存冰激凌蛋糕
The freezer was broken, and we couldn't keep it here.
你看  我就跟你说过提前做好准备
See? This is why I ask you to think ahead, okay?
你征集到50个签名了吗
Do you have your 50 signatures?
差不多了  我征集了34个  可是
Uh, almost. I have 34, but I--
多点少点差不多
Oh. That's the same thing.
可把我说糊涂了
Wow. I'm confused.
-其实是差得多  -绝对
- It's not the same thing. - No.
34和50差得多了
No. 34 is not the same thing as 50,
普通蛋糕和冰激凌蛋糕
just like a cake is not the same thing
-也相差很多  -好吧
- as an ice cream cake. -Right.
-您的意思我懂  但这可是生死攸关的大事  -妈妈
- I get that. Sir, I'm trying to save lives here, - Mom
-我征集够签名再来  -妈  妈
- and I can get you the rest of the signatures. - Mom. Mom. Mom.
-妈  -姑娘们 你们来这干什么
- Mom! -Oh, my god. What are you doing here? Girls.
我们挨家挨户地敲门  又凑齐了20个签名
We--we went door to door and we got you 20 more signatures.
你们真是太贴心了
That is so sweet of you.
你把我们吓得不轻  所以
Well, you were freaking out at us, so...
行了  打住  别破坏气氛
Okay, you know, let's not ruin it.
给你  54个签名
All right, 54 signatures.
怎么样
So what do you say?
拯救生命  从十字路口做起
Let's start saving lives one intersection at a time.
非常感谢你
Okay, thank you very much.
我们会好好研究这事
We will, uh, take these under advisement.
签名留在这里  再次感谢
just leave 'em here, and thank you--
等一下  我可知道"研究"什么意思
Wait a minute. I know what that means.
这下惨了
Oh, here we go.
这是"滚吧"的官方说法
That's Washington-speak for "Get lost."
那个  菲尔
Well, um, wow, Phil.
你来干嘛
what are you doing here?
我是你老公
I'm your husband.
我在守护你的弱点
I'm blindsiding you.
法官大人  请允许我发言
Your honor, permission to approach.
-他不是法官  -准了  说吧
- Not a judge. -I'll allow it.
我就开门见山了  因为事关重大
I'll get straight to the point because this is important,
冰激凌蛋糕又耽搁不得
and that appears to be an ice cream cake.
这不是冰激凌的
Well, it's not!
好吧  我向你们呈上
Okay. I present to you
《停车吧  以生命的名义》
"Stop in the name of life."
开始播放
Kick it.
克里夫·比克斯比
Clive Bixby.
两分钟后在哈里酒吧见  好吗
Can I meet you at Harry's bar in two minutes?
亲爱的  两分钟内我什么都能办到
Baby, I can do anything in two minutes.
我就要加速通过
I'll just speed through
绿叶街和布雷斯托街之间的十字路口了
the intersection of Greenleaf and Bristol.
反正没有停车标志  超速无下限
It's easy 'cause there's no stop sign.
做小孩很快乐
I love being a kid.
青春年少书写大好前程
I have my whole life ahead of me.
不要啊
No!
够了  这个
Okay. Well...
太有说服力了
Powerful.
而且独树一帜  但也证明了我们的观点
And unconventional, but I believe it makes our point,
你们意下如何
so what do you say?
这孩子没事嘛  我倒不太关心大人的情况
Well, the kid was all right. I didn't care for you so much.
可要是我随便就答应
But if I were to give a stop sign
任何人想设立就设立 那么...
to everybody who wanted a stop sign... mm-hmm.
城市将会拥堵不堪
This city would grind to a halt.
-我明白  可是  -谢谢配合  女士
- I understand, sir, but-- - Thank you, ma'am.
-谢谢配合  -听我说几句
- Thank you. Thank you. -Allow me. Allow me.
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我和这女士共同生活了20年
I've lived with this woman for 20 years.
她想要什么
If she wants a stop sign...
就一定得得到
There's gonna be a stop sign.
没错  他说的对
Mm-hmm. He's right.
-句句真言  -是的
- Listen to the man. -Yeah.
还是  不咋地
Still--no good?
不好吗
No bueno?
我回来了
I'm home!
你回来啦  找到斯黛拉了吗
Oh, hey. Did you find Stella?
完狗归杰
Safe and sound. Mm.
我做到了  我没整理  是不是为我感到骄傲
I did it! I left the mess. Aren't you proud of me?
当然啦  你做的太棒了
I sure am. Good for you!
知道吗  刚开始挺艰难的
You know, it wasn't easy at first,
可后来我带莉莉去了公园
But I just-- I took Lily to the park,
把这事完全忘了
and I completely put it out of my mind.
今天我真的克服这道难关了
And I think I really cleared a hurdle today.
太好了  你太令我骄傲了
Oh, that's great. I'm super proud of you,
而现在你也没有任何想打扫的意愿吗
And you're--and you're not even tempted to clean it up now?
-没有  -这下好了
- No! -That's great.
没有  正好你回来了嘛
No, not now that you're home.
看来我得开始打扫了
So guess I'd better get started.
是的
Yeah.
好讨厌哦
I don't like it.
好恶心哦
It's so gross.
我得天哪
Oh, my god.
怎么
What?
我是对的  你就是想让我打扫
I was right. You wanted me to clean it up.
荒谬至极
Oh, that's preposterous.
我才不要站在这里接受你的指责呢
I will not stand here and take this from you.
小卡  得了吧
Oh, Cam!
生活就是一团糟  我就喜欢混乱的感觉
"Life is messy. I love chaos."
你满嘴虚伪谬论  知道吗
You are so full of it. Well, you know what?
没关系  不用担心  一起来糟蹋吧
That's all right. No worries. Hey, come on.
忍忍就过了  生活就是这样
Come on. Just embrace it. It's life.
够了  你这是在无理取闹
Oh! Okay, now that is gratuitous.
-没关系  -不  那是莉莉最爱的谷物早餐
- Oh, it's okay. - No! That's Lily's favorite cereal.
真是荒唐至极
This is ridiculous.
放轻松  莉莉  亲爱的  快过来
Relax! Hey, Lily! Honey, come here!
亲爱的  想要一顶公主帽吗
Sweetheart, do you want a princess hat?
要  要  要
Yes! Yes! Yes!
好的
Okay.
够了  够了  别
Oh. Oh, okay. That--that is enough! No!
你说得对  我不喜欢打扫
You've proven your point. I don't like to clean up.
这活又脏又臭  而且吃完饭后
It's smelly, it's sticky, and after I eat,
我就犯困  只想躺下休息
I'm tired, and I just want to lay down.
而你就弃之不顾  知道我会打扫的
And you put it off, knowing that I would do it?
是的  现在开心了吧
Yes! Are you happy?
我  很  高  兴
Yes... I... Am.
你们好  我是来自领养机构的艾伦·罗伯茨
Hi. I'm Ellen Roberts from the adoption agency.
我是来家庭拜访的
I'm... Here for the home visit.
看来我是得改改习惯了
I might need to tweak my system.
老爸  接招
Hey, dad. Think fast.
苍天大地啊
Sacagawea!
等等  我需要休息下
Wait,wait,wait...I need a break.
打的哥灵魂出窍啊
Oh! John philip sousa!
点击率78了
78 views.
我们就要红了
We are on our way.
那可不是
Yeah, we are.
知道吗  小克  我老爸几乎从来不跟我一起疯
You know what, Lukey? My dad was away a lot.
我可不会让你跟我一样缺少关爱
And I'm not gonna do that to you.
我要做一个好爸爸
I'm gonna be the kind of dad...
你还想玩多久
How many more of these do you wanna do?